kehinde salaudeen

Frontend Developer

kehindesalaudeen222@gmail.com | 08056499531 | 12 oleyo street | Nigeria

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kehnydev/ | https://github.com/kenicodex | https://khenny-portfolio.netlify.app

₽ Profile

Detail-oriented and qualified Frontend Developer able to collaborate with a team, 3+ years experience with JavaScript libraries React, jQuery, and Bootstrap, able to work in an agile scrum environment. I help companies like ReachAfrika (Fintech), Tourbounty (Social Media), Quantum Analytics(EdTech) to build client-side web applications and to translate UI/UX wireframes (like Figma) for company and customer needs into functional, user-friendly, and appealing interactive applications.



Professional Experience

Mid-level Frontend Deveoper, ReachAfrika ☑

2021-11 - present | Ghana

- · Conducted code reviews and provided feedback to other developers to ensure high-quality code
- · Developed and maintained design systems and component libraries to enhance efficiency and consistency
- Led frontend team and assign tasks to junior developers
- Experience with project management applications (Jira and Cliq)

Frontend Developer, *Quantum Analytics* □

2020-07 - 2021-09 | Remote

- Worked with designers to ensure that the website's UI/UX design met the needs of the target audience
- Designed several reusable components which reduced production time by 1 week for the team
- Optimized website performance through SEO and user experience enhancements
- · Tested web-based product functionality and delivered iterations to customers in the sprint method

Frontend Developer, *Tourbounty*

2019-02 - 2020-06 | Yaba lagos, Nigeria

- · Worked well with different developers to address challenges and solve problems collaboratively on the organization's website
- · Developed and maintained user-facing web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Collaborated with designers to implement UI/UX design into functional web pages
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams to deliver projects on time and within budget

Skills

• HTML/CSS/JavaScript

• React

Agile development methodologies

- Angular/Vue.js
- Design tools such as Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD

Education

Bsc Computer science, Caleb University

2018-10 – 2022-08 | ikorodu, Nigeria

- Graduated top 10 of 158 students with a 4.38 CGPA out of 5 attainable
- Help tutorials for student who had problem with programming